# Navneet Mishra

↑ Chennai | **Second Second Se** 

6 Years of experience in web application penetration testing, vulnerability assessment, secure code review and secure application development. Automation and development experience in Java and Python3.

I would like to work in a learning oriented environment. A place where process and policies are simple. A place where working is fun and people work together to make existing things better and simpler. I like taking ownership of assignments and want to work with freedom and choice. I want to explore and work in IOT, mobile, network penetration testing, Python and Linux related things.

# Current project

### **Cognizant | 2017-Present**

- Web application penetration testing
- Secure code review
- Automation
- Assist development team to implement vulnerability fixes

# Previous projects

### Accenture | 2013-2016

- Web application penetration testing
- Secure code review
- Secure web application development
- Automation

# **Automation projects**

#### Project #1

Read pdf report file and extract valuable information like vulnerability name, file name, line number etc. Write the extracted information in another excel file.

Language - Java

# Project #2

Read word report file and extract valuable information like vulnerability name, severity, description, URL, http request and response. Upload the extracted information to online reporting portal.

Language - Python3 API - python-docx, lxml, requests

### Project #3

Read word report file and extract all the vulnerability name, severity, instance numbers and populate this data in another table in the word report.

Language - Python3 API - python-docx

## Project #4

Read pdf report file and extract valuable information and populate another excel file with the extracted information.

Language - Python3 API - pdfminer.six, openpyxl

# **Personal Projects**

Project #1 - College project

Name - ARP Sheath

Details - Developed a program using Java to counter Man in The Middle Attack (MITM) using jpcap (network packet capture library). The program protects the ARP cache of the system as well as that of the access point by sending the correct mapping between IP Address and MAC Address at frequent intervals.

# Project #2

Name - Vulnerable web app for learning

Details - I've designed a small web-app that can be used for learning purpose. It's simple, to-the-point & easy to understand. It has exploitable vulnerabilities and the corresponding patches (patched & unpatched modules). Unpatched part is exploitable, patched part is safe. I've used OWASP ESAPI libraries to patch the vulnerabilities. GitHub

#### Some features

- HTTPS enabled
- XSS, CSRF, SQL injection, click-jacking (patched and unpatched modules) etc.
- Appropriate security flags for session cookie like HttpOnly, secure
- Appropriate security headers like HSTS, X-Frame-Options, X-Content-Type-Options, Referrer-Policy etc.
- Session management
- Role based authorization etc.

#### Skills

- Language Python3, Java
- Web Application Penetration Testing
- Secure Coding (OWASP ESAPI Library)
- Security Tools Fortify, Veracode, Burp Suite Professional, IBM AppScan Standard
- Development Tools Eclipse, Github

## Training and self-learning

- 1 Day IOT Hands-on Workshop by Aseem Jakhar(Payatu Technologies)
- Android application testing video tutorial by Aditya Gupta (Reviewing it)
- Different topics by Troy Hunt on Pluralsight
- Dan Bader Python blog
- Payatu and Attify blog for IOT
- Miscellaneous blogs on Medium

#### Hobbies

- Playing outdoor games; cricket, volleyball, football, badminton. Lead my team in interproject volleyball tournament in Cognizant.
- Listening songs right from 1950s to yo-yo Honey Singh & Stevie Stone; Hindi, Tamil, Telugu; music knows no language.
- Cooking

### Education

B.Tech in Computer Science from KIIT University, Bhubaneshwar, Odisha

### Experience

Accenture: 2013 - 2016Cognizant: 2017 - Present

#### Reference

Mittal Mehta: 91673 48530 (Accenture)Nisha Selvraj: 97903 79565 (Cognizant)